

- +91-72600-66696
- periwalkeshav41@gmail.com
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/keshavperiwal/
- 17 October 1992

EDUCATION

Post Graduate Diploma in Human Resource Management

XLRI, Jamshedpur 2015-2017 | 6.61/8 CGPA

B.Tech. (Instrumentation & Control Engineering)

National Institute of Technology Jalandhar

2010-2014 | 8.28/10 CGPA

HSC / XII

Sacred Heart Convent School Ludhiana, CBSE 2009 - 2010 | 91.6 %

ssc / x

Bhartiya Vidya Mandir Ludhiana, CBSE

2007 - 2008 | 93 %

SKILLS

- HR Business Partnering
- Talent Management
- Employee Engagement
- Organizational Restructuring
- Compensation Budgeting
- Employee Relations & Compliance
- HR Analytics & Data visualisation:
 Tableau, PowerBI
- SAP SuccessFactors / Workday / Oracle HCM

KESHAV PERIWAL

PROFILE

Results-driven HR professional with 8+ years of experience in the BFSI, e-Commerce, and Hospitality sectors. Specializes in HR business partnering, organizational design, performance management, talent management, employee engagement, digital transformation, compensation analytics, and recruitment. MBA from XLRI Jamshedpur, graduating in the top 10% of the class, demonstrating a commitment to excellence and strategic HR initiatives

EXPERIENCE

DEPUTY VICE PRESIDENT, HR

KOTAK MAHINDRA BANK | MUMBAI | August 2022 - Present

Jan'25 onwards

HRBP for Corporate Banking, Private Banking, Treasury, Credit Underwriting, Trade & FX Sales, Operations, Corporate & Asset Reconstruction teams - managing 1300+ headcount

Aug'22 - Dec'24

HRBP for Corporate/Wholesale Banking- Transaction Banking (Product, Cash & Trade Sales, Supply Chain Finance, Technology, BSG, Business Intelligence), Loan Legal Documentation & Account Servicing, Liability businesses managing ~800 employees

- Led organizational restructuring initiatives, enhancing productivity and synergy through talent mapping and integration strategies.
- Responsible for headcount budgeting and staff cost estimation for a budget exceeding INR 400 crores, covering 1400+ employees across 15+ market segments in Wholesale Banking
- Spearheaded talent management and attrition control projects, leveraging data analytics for proactive retention strategies including managing entire Talent & Potential rating for Wholesale Bank with span of control check for effective talent mobility, succession planning & diversity
- Contributed in Leadership Capability Development & Mentoring-360 feedback for leaders; Launched a mentoring program to identify talent, match mentors with mentees, and enabled Individual Development Plans (IDPs)
- Sales Incentive Plan for Portfolio Relationship & Business
 Development Managers for both lending (asset) and CASA
 (liability) focused teams
- Facilitated comprehensive performance appraisal processes including goal setting, assessments, moderation, ratings, promotions, and compensation processes ensuring alignment with organizational goals.

- Leveraging Engagement Surveys (incl. GPTW) and employee feedback through AI based chatbot Amber
- Managed employee relations, resolving grievances in collaboration with compliance teams.
- Supported in campus hiring, onboarding interns (rolling-out PPOs) and management trainees to develop future leaders while managing lateral hiring processes

HR BUSINESS PARTNER

AMAZON DEVELOPMENT CENTER | HYDERABAD | November 2020- May 2022

- HRBP for Seller Support Operations teams; handled both onsite and virtual contact center (VCC) teams; managed client group of approx. 800-1000 employees
- Led talent reviews with a focus on performance management and employee development.
- Provided strategic HR consultation to line managers on organizational processes, including onboarding, policy compliance, and employee relations.
- Managed compensation initiatives, reviewing salary actions for appraisals, promotions, and transfers to align with organizational objectives.

HR ANALYST

OYO HOTELS | GURGAON | June 2019- September 2020

- Led People Analytics projects like creating HR data visualization and dashboards using Tableau, focusing on key metrics like NPS, engagement, headcount, diversity, and attrition, People Manager Scorecard, Process Compliance Scorecard, Analytics Playbook, and Recruiter Incentives computation
- Contributed to the Oracle cloud HRMS implementation project across India, Indonesia, Malaysia conducting extensive SIT/UAT (Systems Integration Testing/User Acceptance Testing) and creating process flow maps using Visio for clarity and efficiency
- Acted as Solution Architect for an in-house HR Ticketing platform (Helpdesk); designed process flow maps for various HR workflows, curated architecture and configuration workbook
- Launched the Amber AI-based engagement chatbot across nine countries (India, Indonesia, Malaysia, Mexico, Philippines, Thailand, Saudi Arabia, UAE, Vietnam), supporting over 10,000 associates in India

HR BUSINESS PARTNER

RELIANCE CAPITAL GROUP | MUMBAI | May 2017 - May 2019

Reliance General Insurance

- Managed workforce activities across Maharashtra, Gujarat, Madhya Pradesh, and Goa, and spearheaded the launch of the Employee Satisfaction (ESAT) survey
- Developed a Learning Management System and conducted a Training Needs Identification (TNI) to assess organizational training requirements, implementing various product, process, and behavioral training modules.
- Led the rollout and implementation of Oracle Fusion and Taleo HRMS
- Prepared periodic HR dashboards for senior management, resolved queries through a chatbot, revamped the intranet portal, and designed a careers microsite

·Reliance Capital Limited

- Managed the complete employee life cycle for corporate functions, overseeing recruitment, onboarding, training needs analysis, employee engagement initiatives, performance appraisal cycles, exit interviews, and HR operations audits.
- Contributed to the adoption of Workplace by Facebook as a communication tool, promoting Workplace and Work chat mobile apps as alternatives to WhatsApp

INTERNSHIP

VODAFONE | MOHALI | April 2016 - June 2016

Project: Managing the Millennial Workforce

GRADUATE ENGINEER TRAINEE-MAINTENANCE & EQUIPMENT RELIABILITY

HINDUSTAN PETROLEUM - MITTAL ENERGY LTD. | BATHINDA | June 2014 to June 2015